

KIM EDWARD V. OCLIDA

Birth date: OCTOBER 26, 1994

Civil status: Single

Address: 93-45 Cattleya St. Mindanao Ave., Brgy. Bahay Toro

Project 8 , Quezon City, 1106 **Home Tel.:** +63-38-4110211

Cell: +63-9555492380

Email: kimedwardoclida@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

I am seeking a challenging position where I could utilize my acquired engineering and technical skill, enhance my hard-working habits, and contribute to the company's best interests.

EDUCATION ATTAINMENT

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering

Holy Name University

Janssen Heights, Dampas District, Tagbilaran City, Bohol, Philippines 6300

SY: 2011 - 2016

CAREER SUMMARY

Experienced in field of technical and industrial control, exposure in the field of instrumentation, commissioning and functional testing, maintenance, calibration, hydrographic survey, diving equipment maintenance and medical equipment functional testing and also a front-end developer with a knowledge of HTML CSS Javascript and React.JS

Skills

- Electronic Repair, Electronics Design
- Instrument Calibration and maintenance
- Frontend Developer: HTML CSS Javascript and React.JS
- Computer Networking, IT Technical Support

ACHIEVEMENTS

ECT Board Examination Passer

October 2017

Won 2nd place for best student Design Projects

Project title: Design and Implementation of a Multi-crop Gardening System for

Urban Areas, Using Web Application

Date: March 3-5, 2016

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

COMPANY: Subsea Services Inc.

POSITION: Electronics Engineer / Maintenance Engineer

DATE: June 2019 - May 2023

COMPANY: Creative Skin Medequip Inc. POSITION: Electronics Service Engineer

DATE: March 2019 - June 2019

COMPANY: Green Leaf Day Spa (Philippines)

Position: Spa Equipment Technician / Maintenance

DATE: April 04, 2016 to June 11, 2016

April 06, 2015 to May 31, 2015(Summer Job) April 13, 2014 to May 31, 2014 (Summer Job) April 07, 2013 to May 31, 2013(Summer Job)

COMPANY: Bohol Community Cable TV Systems, INC. (OJT)

POSITION: INTERN

DATE: April 2015 to May 2015

DUTIES AND RESPONISIBILIES

As an Electronics Engineer/ Maintenance Engineer:

- Performed and conduct precision positioning of the area to be surveyed through data acquisition to process a clear visual marine environment these also involve measuring and mapping the underwater surfaces and studying the morphology (construction) of the seabed.
- Maintenance of the equipment before and after the Hydrographic Survey to ensure the data and equipment integrity.
- Responsible for proper distribution of task to the field personnel to ensure successful Hydrographic survey activity.
- Verify the data gathered are accurate before we end the survey activity.
- Solving Technical issues encountered during the Survey.
- Commissioning of newly installed winch system for boat tugging and Take of Materials prior for Installation

As a Medical Equipment Engineer:

- Commissioning and functional testing of medical equipment prior for hand over to the client
- Trained Medical personnel on how to properly use the Equipment and its principle of operation.
- Troubleshooting on defective equipment and make reports on the equipment that need repair or replacement.
- Preventive maintenance of Facial Medical Equipment's to ensure its working integrity.

Equipment: Smaxel CO2 Laser Treatment, Onda Deka Coolwave, Basic Facial Treatment machine Etc.

As a Spa Equipment technician/Maintenance:

 Preventive maintenance of spa equipment to assure its working integrity and inform immediately the manager when something needs to be repaired to avoid downtime of spa services. equipment: Sauna, Facial Machine, Air Conditioning units, Water Heater, CCTV System, Intercoms, Sound System, and Internet system.

- Testing and commissioning of Sauna equipment prior to safe operational condition.
- Imparted training to the therapist on the proper use of spa equipment.
- Troubleshooting on defective equipment and make reports on the equipment that need repair or replacement.

Instrumentation and Control Technician (NCII):

Learned various processes in the system which include Water Treatment, Steam Generation, Steam Turbine, Steam Condensate, Power Generation, Boiler Control Automation, Fuel Gas for Hydrocarbon gas cracking, Pygas Hydrogenation, Aromatics, and Butadiene Extraction, HVAC, Fire, and Gas system. The task involved Loop checking from field instrument devices through the field junction box, marshaling cabinet to the Distributed Control System (DCS) / Integrated Control and Safety System (ICSS), Inspection of devices, and ensuring that they conformed to the standards of installation and specifications before testing to be carried out and put in punch list items that are not qualified to the specifications for further rectification. Tick all necessary remarks against ITR checklists.

Functional checkout, calibration and testing of all associated field instrument devices within the approved Ready for Commissioning Systems. Devices are Smart Transmitters (Pressure, Differential Pressure, Temperature, Flow, and Level) Sensors. Thermocouple and RTD Temperature sensors, Smoke Detectors, Heat Detectors, Gas Detectors and Flame Detectors. Smart type Control Valves, Solenoid Valves and Air Operated and Deluge Valves with aid of Calibration equipment such as Druck Pressure Calibrator, Fluke Multimeter, Hart Field Communicator model 475, Solo A5 Smoke Detector Aerosol tester and Solo 330 Aerosol Smoke Dispenser Tester.

Ensure proper documentation after the testing has been done and record all tested loops in the ITR (Inspection and Test Record forms) for package hand over.

As an Intern:

- Installation of coaxial cable for TV signal
- Checking the signal strength coming from the main source to the TV antenna input
- Cabling of TV signal cable from the tapping terminal going through the house to the TV Cable antenna input.
- Estimation of coaxial cable in preparation for installation

TRAININGS AND SEMINARS ATTENDED

- Instrumentation and control servicing (NCII)
- Mechatronics Servicing (NCII)
- Google IT Technical Support Fundamentals (Certificate)
- The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking (Certificate)
- Global Permit to Work Training Shell (GPTW)
- Electronic Permit to Work Training Shell (ePTW)
- Shell Philippines Supervisory Training
- Responsive Web Design (FreeCodeCamp)

I hereby certify that the above information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Kim Edward Oclida